Mickael JEANROY +33 6 88 94 51 85 mickael.jeanroy@gmail.com https://mjeanroy.dev https://github.com/mjeanroy https://twitter.com/mickaeljeanroy

Professional Objective

Software engineer since 2008, I am mainly interested by web technologies, web architecture and web application security.

My objective is to obtain a position of full stack developer where I can use my skills and experience to develop robust and wonderful web applications.

Main Skills

Front: JavaScript, CSS, JavaScript Frameworks (AngularJS, Angular, React, VueJS).

Back: Java, Java Frameworks (Spring, JPA / Hibernate, tests frameworks such as JUnit,

AssertJ, Mockito, or DBUnit), basic knowledge in Python, Scala and Kotlin.

Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MySQL, Elasticsearch, Basic knowledge of Redis.

Others: Git, Gerrit, Test Driven Development.

Open Source

For personal projects, I developed some libraries / small applications that are publicly available on GitHub: https://github.com/mjeanroy and described on my personal website: https://mjeanroy.dev/projects.

Work Experience

11/2017 – PRESENT Malt Community

Software Engineer, technical leader.

Design and implementation of the whole platform:

- Front: JavaScript, TypeScript, VueJS.
- Back: Java (Spring, JOOQ).
- Database: MongoDB, PostgreSQL, ElasticSearch, Redis
- Messaging: RabbitMQ
- CI/CD: Maven and Yarn as build tools, Bamboo as continuous integration

12/2012 – 11/2017 **Zenika**

Software Engineer, technical leader in Java and web development. AngularJS and React trainer.

Design and implementation of web applications (for various french clients):

Front: Javascript (AngularJS, Angular, ReactJS).

- Back: Java (Spring, JPA / Hibernate).
- Database: MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, ElasticSearch
- Messaging: RabbitMQ, Kafka
- CI/CD: Maven and Gulp as build tools, Jenkins as continuous integration server, Sonar.

09/2011 – 11/2012 **Arkoon Network Security**

Software Engineer, technical leader in Java and web development Design and implementation of a web application used to manage AMC (Arkoon Management Center) Servers.

- Front: JavaScript (jQuery, BackboneJS, requireJS) and HTML5 technologies (Websocket, pushState and history API)
- Back: Play Framework v2 (Java) and Python.

08/2008 – 08/2011 Orange Business Services

Java / Web Developer.

Design and implementation of web applications:

- Front: Development using Flex or Javascript (jQuery) technologies.
- Server: Java (Spring, JPA / Hibernate)
- Design and implementation of REST API used to communicate between heterogeneous applications.

Education

2013 - 2014	MOOC on Coursera
	Algorithms, Design And Analysys, part 1 (2013) and part 2 (2014)
	Functional programming in Scala (2014)
2005 – 2008	INSA (Institut National des Sciences Appliquées) in Lyon, France
	Diplôme d'Ingénieur en Informatique (equivalent to a master degree in computer
	science)
2003 – 2005	Institut Universitaire de Technologie Génie Informatique in Villeurbanne, France
2002 – 2003	Baccalauréat Scientifique, "option Math Spé" in La Boisse, France, graduated
	with honours ("mention Assez-Bien").

Languages

French: mother language

English: Good working knowledges

Miscellaneous

Passionate about cinema (particularly gangster's movies from 70's to 90's such as "Godfather", "Goodfellas" etc.).

Passionate about J.R.R Tolkien books ("Lord of the rings", "The hobbit" or "The Silmarillion").